

My Contact

Cheriedavis126@gmail.com

(859-492-4887

Lexington, Kentucky

linkedin.com/in/cherieadavis/

Expertise

- M.S. Corporate Communications
- · B2B, B2C & services marketing
- Digital marketing
- Strategic marketing planning & analysis
- · Budgeting & client billing
- SaaS & CRM management
- Leadership & team development
- Startup marketing
- Business development
- · Sales support

Key Experience & Industries

- A/E/C (architecture, engineering, construction)
- · Digital Marketing
- White space analysis
- Software Marketing
- Healthcare Marketing

Education Background

Florida State University

Master of Science, Corporate and Public Communications

Tallahassee, Florida

Marshall University

Bachelor of Arts, Public Relations Huntington, West Virginia

CHERIE DAVIS

Marketing & Communications

Summary

Dedicated marketing and communications professional with over a decade of experience in the field. Expertise spans a range of areas, including strategic communications and marketing, digital marketing strategies, branding, social media, public relations, marketing research, marketing/competitive analysis, sponsorship development, and account management

Professional Experience

The Rainmaker Institute | DM Account Manager August 2023- Present Remote

About The Rainmaker Insitute:

The Rainmaker Institute is a company that provides marketing and business development solutions specifically tailored for law firms. They offer services such as legal marketing strategies, website design, search engine optimization (SEO), and other tools to help law firms attract and retain clients. The focus is on helping legal professionals grow their practices through effective marketing techniques.

Support the Digital Marketing team as the SEO Lead, driving online visibility and enhancing digital presence. With a focus on search engine optimization, I lead initiatives to optimize website content, improve rankings, and increase organic traffic.

Key Responsibilities

- Leads strategy for SEO for all clients in the Digital Marketing team.
- Led internal coordination of content development, PR strategy, and SEO insights, ensuring client satisfaction with a focus in client retention.
- Works with important vendors and industry leaders outside of the agency to educate and provide digital strategies for all clients within the agency. Local citation scores have increased on average by 9%, page speed increased by 14%, and domain authority by 2% increase.
- Project managed all aspects of building a new website for clients in WordPress and WebFlow.
- Crafted C-Suite level reports and presentations for the agency's executive pitches.
- Created SEO strategy for sales and internal marketing team, including full site SEO audit, website UX audit, and keyword quidelines.

Professional Experience

RossTarrant Architects | Marketing Coordinator

April 2022- March 2023 Lexington, Kentucky

About RossTarrant Architects:

RTA is an architectural design firm with a singular mission: enhancing education through great design. RTA has been providing architecture, interior design, landscape architecture, and civil engineering services to K-12 school districts and postsecondary clients, focusing on sustainability and building longevity within each unique environment.

Support the VP of Marketing and Business Development across all marketing strategies, including digital marketing, advertising, sponsorship, C- level presentations, event strategy/management, tradeshow marketing, and responses to RFPs.

Support the VP of Marketing and Business Development across all marketing strategies, including digital marketing, advertising, sponsorship, C-level presentations, event strategy/management, tradeshow marketing, and responses to RFPs.

Key Responsibilities

- · Maintains, controls and updates all CRM and database including current client database, VIP client list, and prospective client lists.
- Work closely with principles and traveling architects at the firm to create compelling marketing collateral that supports business development and market expansion.
- Responds and identifies compatible services for Requests for Proposals. Development of new proposal templates and assists in strategy meetings.
- Developing engaging social media content for the firm, including Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Google, and Instagram posts. Saw an increase of 42% in social media reach and an increase of 25% in engagement rate year over year.
- Demonstrating the firms' unique knowledge of sustainable design principles of roofing envelope systems, floor heaving, and MEP renewal designs and consulting work through video, digital content, and RFPs.
- Orchestrating content and submissions for awards within architecture/engineering associations focusing on LEED Gold, LEED Silver, ENERGY STAR, and Net Zero projects.
- Highlighting sustainable design practices through tradeshow marketing, content creation, digital marketing, and internal signage.
- Focusing on recruitment marketing through digital content creation, including social media content, blogs, and employee spotlight features. Particular focus on principals and employees with certifications within LEED, ENERGY STAR, DGNB, and A4LE.
- Responsible for writing, creating content, and collecting all information for monthly employee newsletters and quarterly outreach newsletters.

Lynn Imaging | Marketing Director

October 2018 - April 2022 Lexington, Kentucky

About Lynn Imaging:

Lynn Imaging is a Construction Information Management company providing high-speed digital printing, electronic data storage, cloud solutions, and large-format equipment sales.

Spearheaded all marketing efforts to include digital marketing strategies for three locations and three separate brands, including SEO, SEM, social media marketing, and content/blog development campaigns.

Key responsibilities:

- Pioneered new websites, including website development, SEO, content, and navigation which have driven an average of 3,000 unique monthly visits, and website requests for estimates have increased 15% year over year.
- Formulated and implemented social media, marketing, and PR strategy drive marketing goals.
- Developed social media content and scheduled monthly updates using Hootsuite; increased Facebook likes by 40% and Instagram follows by 420%.
- Planned quarterly large-scale events, open houses, customer appreciation, and product launches to raise brand awareness and generate new leads for the sales team. Was able to increase average event sales by \$10,000 due to efficient targeting for events.
- Evaluated marketing data and conducted competitive analysis using Google Analytics & Search Console, Hootsuite Insights, Facebook Insights, and Hubspot, inspiring the creation of the new website and website content.
- Demonstrated the company's commitment to recycling and green practices externally and internally through multi-channel marketing efforts. Large focus on HP and Xerox recycling toner cartridges and large equipment.
- Advocated sustainability and the company's green initiatives to the customer database. Including the company's recycling program, used
 equipment sales, and equipment trade-in programs. Planned, marketed, and managed education and outreach on these programs
 through targeted events online and in person.
- Repositioned marketing strategy to align with target audiences, driving lead increases of 16% in organic traffic and 70% more keywords ranked.
- Developed direct mail and marketing content increasing sales opportunities by 22% YOY, with an increase in correlating close rates of 32%.
- Work directly with HP and Xerox on Partner Programs, and keep up to date on the latest technology, content, and collateral to implement into the marketing strategy.